hopefully that's the thumbnail right
there really angry Rob or constipated
one of the two here's the thing Chad GPT
is not bad but when it is bad it is
really bad and I'm going to show you why
this is a very specific example that I
was using today um of Chachi and and
actually I'm going to show you a good
example and I'm going to show you a bad
example and I I see that I'm clipping
I'm sorry um you know deal with it um
all right so let's let's actually go to
an example of chbt working I realize
this is small on the screen I'm sorry uh
we're going to come back to this one
right here uh this is this is Chad this
is me asking zertek which actually this
is really cool um I'm gonna give you a
couple examples of chpt actually totally
working and the reason I'm paying a
subscription for it and I really love it
there's the wife noises I told you about
yeah she's she's like doing kitchen
stuff I mean it's Ambiance considered
Ambiance all right anyway
um CL is goed for code okay I'll have to
try that so I was asking about zertek
treating long covid which I've had a
problem with I'm having a hard time
concentrating in a different video about
that um and so antihist are anecdotally
some way to do that and I've been so I
was able to ask it some stuff about that
and then um I'm trying to give you
another positive
example uh there's a bunch of attempts
to try to do the thing that I'm doing
I'm writing code with and it comes
pretty damn close it did give me some
ideas uh that was some go- C from before
you can pause the video if you want to
see any of those those um I actually
asked it about naps
recently um what's the optimum size for
a for a nap uh I think that's like back
there I'm trying to get back to the one
piece of good code this the ideal code
that that this is and a lot of you guys
already know this so you know people who
are taking sides on the chat GPT thing
as usual it's usually not black or white
it's not one side or the other it's
actually a really good tool if you use
it right uh you just but don't depend on
it permanently you want to make sure to
check your stuff obviously I asked a lot
of question about sweet pee and music
and stuff like that it's really great at
that it's like way way faster than
checking with Google about things that I
want to ask it really quickly um but so
let me show you this
um one of one a long time ago I asked
that I said hey can you just can you
just count all the leading spaces on the
on the function right and it wrote this
function for me really quick and that
that kind of thing my friends that is
worth it because you know no amount of
time yes I can I'm a fast tyer whatever
I'm actually not a very fast programmer
you're being why would you be this loud
right now I literally told you that I
was just
about okay I'm gonna wait I'm gonna
pause I'm gonna walk into my office I'm
gonna walk into my office to complete
the video rather than upset my wife by
you
know are you are you making Hamish
things tomato
sa o that sounds good okay all right so
I'm going into the other room going to
my yoga room SL office it's got a
totally different light s you know what
how about we go out on the patio over
here how about that look so I promise
you we're not we're gonna look this is a
look just be happy you have a video I
don't want to hear about it in the
comments why do you I don't want to hear
okay this is this is what you get
otherwise you get no video okay
so CH Chad gbt bad right no Chad gbt is
good and bad and here we go so we have
count the leading spaces and you see how
it does that that's the kind of code
that it just like go is a pain in the
ass to do this kind of thing and it just
spit it out and it works and immediately
you can tell it works just by looking at
it and and that's where Chad is really
great I told you about you know looking
at minor quaries is really great but let
me show you um another another area
where it's really really wrong and this
is this is what made me want to make
this video okay so I've been writing
this I've been writing this supposedly
easy code it's not easy for me because I
have long Co right now my brain is just
like not
working and you can tune in with me
later about that but and it seriously
it's taking me three days to make this
very minimal you know function if you
want to know more about that tune in but
um and I was actually trying to get AI I
was trying to get chat gbt to do it for
me because it's super dumb code that I
really don't care about and it was about
that time that I said you know I was
like you know what and if you don't know
go I'll tell you about a little bit
so um in go
you can when it's the objectoriented
programming part of
go allows you to do stuff like
this right you can define a a type like
this this is invalid code by the way as
you can see from my screen this is
invalid code um and but you can see here
go told me that was okay and you can
inline a struct you you can do that you
can inline a struct but you cannot
inline methods it's always been true for
go and and you know I was wondering if
maybe something could change to 122 that
I didn't see in the release notes
because I didn't check the release notes
for 121 and22 probably should go through
that and make a video about that but the
point of this is that you know I was
like damn that would be really cool
because then it would this is a totally
stupid example that made by the way it's
using exported you would never do that
you use lowercase right because you
don't this is all within the this is
almost in a function scope it's all
minimally uh you know so but this this
kind of stuff usually comes right here
so so this is completely valid go code
all right and as you can see the the
errors went away from my automated you
know MIM thing and that is that compiles
right that will totally compile um but
the one Chad gbt told me uh so so but
this this this is the danger and this is
the reason for this video Okay the
reason for this video is is because of
how definitive chat gbt sounded and it's
very very dangerous because chat gbt
sounds that has has this error of
authority like it like it really knows
what it's talking about when it clearly
doesn't it's shbt is like your very very
knowledgeable friend who's [__]
totally wrong sometimes but then doubles
down on how wrong they are rather than
come around right that brand only the
difference with Chad GPT is is that if
you give it new information it will
unlike your your pedantic you know
know-it-all friend it will actually
change its mind on you and I want to
read this to you it's very important um
that you see at least this example if
you before you make any decisions about
AI uh specifically large language models
AI by the way is not the same as large
language models and uh Adam ruins
everything did a whole thing where he's
like throwing AI under the bus and
calling everybody stupid for using it no
he's stupid for saying that that's ai's
got tremendous value um including these
you know significantly wrong large
language models on occasion so so but
but I just wanted to show you this let's
after the zertek thing has goang always
allowed creation of name types like
structs within the body of a
function because I thought I was going
crazy right I thought that I was trying
to do something that I wasn't seeing the
errors pop up from the you know the the
real- time uh syntax Checker I have
working with my B and and it was and you
know it turned out to be something else
it turned out to be that you can do the
inline struct you can even do name
structs but you cannot add methods and a
method and go is is a is a is a a
function with a receiver that's what
this is this is a receiver that says
it's kind of like hanging a a function
off of a struct right which I really
love because at runtime even um actually
no not at runtime but I mean that's a
different thing you'd have to do youd
have to do an assignment you can't do it
at run time at all so forget I said but
you can have a receiver and do this
thing all right so you could have this
oops you can have
this right that's totally Val ago but
you cannot that's stupid to do that you
would probably do this
instead right you have a lower case
because you don't care about the scope
you want it to be lower you it's nice
it's easy to remember it reminds you
that it's it's a a struct that you have
in here you can even you can even do
Anonymous strs which I had done that's
what this was before I did this you can
do type you know item I guess uh is a
struct oh no wait you can do inline
structs which are really cool it's very
SE like to do this uh where you actually
assign two one that you're going to
reuse like and you don't want to use uh
some sort of map notation which is
really Heavy D heavy-handed so you do
you could do this is an inline struct um
so yeah you do item equals struct and
you can Define especially if it's an INT
if it's like they're the same type this
is really great you can say uh count um
and you could say uh um last or
something and then make it int and then
you can actually do that you can
actually initialize it with an initial
value the default initializer values for
for instance are zero so that you don't
need to do that and go anyway that's an
inline stru right now that is normal to
use this is normal to use but as soon as
you try to to hang a function off of it
you have an error okay so that's all the
go that you need to know
here uh to to be able to follow along
with my conclusion okay so so there's
like no no I don't even know that's not
even GH syntax it's never been goh
syntax what the hell are you doing right
I don't think you can do this wouldn't
that be cool if you
could oh my
God I may have discovered
something no wait a
second wait a
second the scope of this type is within
main but this wait what what what is
going on here I think I just just to
find something El about ghost so maybe
chat GPT is sort of right why didn't
that bark of me is that going to comp
so you can Define the function you can
hang a function off of an off of a type
it you have to do it outside of the
outside of the containing body of
the if that's always been a go thing
then I'm going to stand corrected in
chat gbt was kind of bright even though
the example they gave me was totally
dead wrong let's try this this this
might be worth it all by itself go
run oh here we go undefined person item
declared and not
used well that I know well we don't need
that one there also S as person let's go
look at this person right here
Persona
person p.
greet I if this works I'm G to freak out
undefined person I thought so okay
that's what I would expect all right so
yeah that's what I that's what I've
always expect this this would be
completely wrong because person is
supposed to only be visible to step
within the main body of the punk that's
the reason for using strs like this
because you don't want to pollute your
Global name space with you know uh with
a bunch of stuff you want to put and so
if that had worked I would have been
really surprised we already know that
this does not work for the reasons that
you're getting there and okay so let's
proceed to you know throw chat P under
the bus for this so because for for one
one second there I'm my second guessing
myself which is really great Chad GPT
this is where I went wrong and you
cannot be me and you can make a better
decisions okay I've started to trust
Chad BPT probably way more than I should
I've been using it for a lot I've been
using it for route planning on my bike
I've been all kinds of stuff I've been
talking to it like it's real I've been
saying telling it thank you and my
mistake was that I started I started
really trusting it and I was like okay
Chach BT so did go did the language
change I said did the language change is
has it always been possible that I can
actually add um strs within the body of
my function and and it said yes go has
always allowed the creation of name
types such as structs with the body but
function
this feature has been available since go
releases this is a very specific answer
in go you can define a struct or a
custom type within a function although
the scope of that type will be
eliminated the function isine that
that's that I knew right and then and
then here's here's the part that's both
good and bad so it actually gives me an
example here this is completely valid
code kind of stupid because you know
person is exported even though there's
no exporting happening in this case
person is blah blah blah all right now
there's something that I like about
chaty P here and something that I really
we hate the first thing I like is like
is can they have receiver methods I
that's what 1 two 3 four five that's
five that's a fword question to Chad GPT
that's based on the previous context so
I didn't have to rewrite that if I was
doing Google searches and stuff that
would have taken me a lot longer to ask
but chat GPT this is one the thing I do
like about chat GPT contential queries
is that I can actually supplement it and
chat pgp does a pretty damn good job of
taking the previous context of the thing
that we were talking about and adding on
information and that's what it did it
just got the answer wrong so it said can
they have receiver methods it knew what
a receiver method was now this this is
where it gets really weird okay this is
where it's your it's your friend it's
wrong right I mean it's it knew what a
receiver method was which blows my mind
I mean that's just totally blows my mind
yes types including structs defined
within a function in goil can have
receiver methods this is categorically
positively false I've already proven it
we tried to compile the code that is
code that won't compile and never has
compiled however the methods associated
with these types limited to scope and
value okay this is wrong and then and
then it proceeds to even double down on
how wrong it is it actually gives you an
example of an embedded faction this this
code will not compile that is the basis
of the code you're looking at on the
other part of the screen I copy and
pasted it as is and immediately got all
these warnings and errors and I was like
I didn't think this was going to run but
I was like God it is so sure that this
is g to run it is so sure it was very
convincing and I was like
okay I guess you know more than I do
Chad gbd and so then I went back to look
at this stuff um short person is
definest telling me all about it and
everything which is really great and
then I tried it and it wouldn't compile
and I told it it was full of [__] and
this is actually really fun this is also
kind of a kind of a lesson in in in
deescalation so Chad GPT is really good
at de-escalating being a [__] this is
kind of funny so this is completely
wrong what are you a noob goang program
this has never been true you're
absolutely right I apologize for the
confusion in my previous response in go
name types like strs cannot be defined
inside function bodies and this has
never been allowed in the
language you can Define types in the
package level but not within a function
if you attempt to declare a type inside
the function go will throw a compile
time error here's the example of what of
what isn't allowed of what isn't allowed
and go okay and you know what's really
sad about this is that this is also
wrong this is totally allowed it's right
there I just did it go chat GPT does not
know does not know that you can Define
types within a function but not their
method
functions it doesn't know that and it's
look at that it's even tell me it tried
to correct itself and it actually told
you something else that is wrong and I
want to say this is a result of a
compilation this will not I just did it
it's not a compilation error you dumb
piece of [__] okay so then I went back
here the correct approach is to do this
put it outside it is good but you don't
have to do that again I apologize for
the mistake and I got mad I got mad and
I said then why would you tell me that
you could do it and even make an example
that won't even compile and go and then
there's the deescalation part I
appreciate your patience and I
completely understand your frustration
you're absolutely
right tell somebody they're right and
and if if you had a fight with them and
my initial response was incorrect what
yeah the the mistake I I made was
entirely on me and I appreciate you
bringing my attention there is a lesson
about life to be had in there chbt may
be an AI but because it's an AI it has
WFTS of information and data
scientifically speaking that tell it
that when it's wrong it needs to
deescalate immediately or people will
stop paying for it and I'm like reading
that going okay fine all right all right
you're right I was right you were wrong
and I was right all right let's move on
and most humans won't do that ever and
if you're in Tech you know this uh and
go name type such as they'll find some
way to be right on the side they'll make
an angle to make it right because
they're human backfire effect um Ino
name types such as strs cannot be
declared inside functions [__] I
just did it okay um here's here's the
thing so and then it gives me an example
now this this is actually compilable
good code um they did export the person
for no reason which is probably okay
especially if you're using the internal
package go watch another video for that
what is the internal package if you
don't know what the internal package is
you should use it everybody should use
their internal
package okay so let's go here uh the
example will work perfectly because the
p the St person is defined in the
package level I genuinely appreciate you
catching your okay so so the takeaway
from this video is is very basic right
the takeaway is chat gbd is really
really great at getting you to where you
need to be and getting you to ask the
questions you need to ask and answering
some questions for you really quickly uh
it's also really great at doing the
mundane coding that's super easy um you
know like iterating and enumerating and
that kind of stuff that takes you just
way too long to write the code and and
and for that reason I am truly training
myself to become a chbd prompt
engineer and I this is this is this is a
total 180 for me because I when I when I
first saw AI I was like oh my God it's
never going to replace people there's
going to have to be people there it's
true but it's like sitting next to a guy
in a cubicle who thinks he knows
everything and is pretty damn smart but
doesn't know everything but they're like
well-rounded about more things than you
would ever imagine they're basically
Chad gbt is basically your best cubicle
buddy I mean I can get answers from Chad
gbt like in a fraction of the time that
it takes me to go do even a command line
search and if you know me you know that
I do a lot of really you know
millisecond level command line searching
because I don't like being able to
search really quickly is the single
greatest advantage and the number one
skill you need to learn Beyond knowing
how to learn learning how to learn and
let's talk about education for a second
and I'm going to go ahead and wrap up
with that when I the thing that got me
to turn around you know my position on
AI some years ago year and a half ago or
so was my good buddy uh lgm Bob um who
teaches at University at least he did
tell very recently moving into the
corporate sector again um to told me how
great it was for Education he's like
this is a fantastic tool for Education
now and I want to put a bullet point on
that right now yes it's great for ation
but in this case you would be
totally pardon my one French word [__]
if you use this if you use this and you
went and as with all the competence and
assurance that chat GPD did you created
code that wouldn't even
compile you'd be laughed out of any kind
of job interview for go programming
anywhere now most people who do that
kind of interview don't expect you to
know all the answers up front they do
expect you to do the things in test and
compile they would this kind of thing
they would say compile it and and by the
way this dumb friend of ours chbt who's
also really smart doesn't have the
ability to compile the code to see if it
works so so so don't give up your
personal network of friends because
you're professional L group your
programming group your Meetup Group your
favorite twitch streamer you know these
kind of things are still going to be
really relevant for you because when you
ask those questions when you've done all
the work to answer the question for
yourself like the autodidact that you
are and you can't get the answer you've
got to turn to your professional
Learning Network not just Chad GPT Chad
GPT is one member of your professional
Learning Network and I'm going to
conclude with that don't ever trust it
completely just like you never trust
anybody else you know um
and yeah I was going to ask you your
your in your opinions on love and trust
there's a statement in a movie that
we're watching right now or a thing the
old man it's called where they they say
you can either trust somebody or you can
love them but you can't do both and I
feel like that's how you should go with
Chad
GPT you should never trust chb but you
can love it you just should never trust
it I I'm done now I promise I'm done now
I'm going to go turn off the recording